Claire Falkenstein
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Correspondence, 1931-1997, Series 2:; (Box 5-13; 9 linear feet)
  Gallery and museum correspondence is with Anderson Gallery, Bolles Gallery, Coos Art Museum, Galerie Anderson-Mayer (Paris), Galerie Stadler (Paris), Gallery Mayer (Paris), Jack Rutberg Fine Arts (Los Angeles), Los Angeles Museum of Art, Malvina Miller (New York), Martha Jackson Gallery (New York), Otto Seligman Gallery, Polly Friedlander Gallery, and the San Francisco Museum of Art, among many others. This series also contains postcards and Christmas cards.
  Outgoing letters are arranged first in chronological order, followed by incoming letters arranged alphabetically by name correspondent. Miscellaneous files for each letter of the alphabet contain single letters from each correspondent. Christmas cards and postcards are arranged at the end of the series.
  - Copies and Excerpts of Outgoing Letters to Various Individuals, circa 1946-1961, (11 folders) (Box 5, Folder 1-11)
  - Claire Falkenstein to Richard McCarthy, circa 1951-1960, 1989, 1994, (10 folders) (Box 5, Folder 12-21)
  - Letters to Richard McCarthy from Various Individuals, circa 1950-1958 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - 3 EP, LTD, 1982, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Miscellaneous Ac-Ap, 1958-1994 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Miscellaneious Ar-Au, 1958-1994 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Abraxas Gallery, circa 1980-1984 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Carla Accardi, circa 1955-1974 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Julien Alvard, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - American Contemporary Gallery, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Becky Anderson, 1971-1974, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Moo and Hunk Anderson, 1982-1991 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Anderson Gallery, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Anita Shapolsky Gallery, circa 1986-1993 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Anna Head School, 1970-1995 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Arbitrage Art Gallery, circa 1985 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Architectural Art Services, 1961, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Armand Hammer Museum of Art and Cultural Center, UCLA, 1995-1996 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Jean Arp, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Arts and Architecture, 1949, 1955, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Franco Assetto, circa 1955-1984 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Atelier Royce, circa 1975-1993 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Jeanne Aurel-Schneider, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Miscellaneous Ba-Bo, 1951-1994 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Miscellaneous Br-Bu, 1951-1994 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Charlotte Baker, circa 1931-1995 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Baltimore Museum of Art, 1959-1960 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Helen and Bud Barnard, 1975-1981 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Jim Batliff, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Anne Baxter, circa 1979-1986 (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Betty Parsons Gallery, 1950-1953 (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Edward Biberman, 1970-1974 (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Helen Bickel, circa 1950-1978, (3 folders) (Box 5, Folder 52-54)
  - Jeff Bickel, circa 1960, 1969, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - Mary Lou Bickel, 1961, 1967, 1986-1991 (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - Anna Bing, 1976-1987 (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - Seymour and Elyanne Boardman, circa 1950-1952 (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - George Bohrman1978-1980 (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - Bolles Gallery, circa 1958-1959 (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - Alain Bosquet, circa 1956-1957 (Box 5, Folder 61)
  - Dorr Bothwell, 1950-1951 (Box 5, Folder 62)
  - Georges Boudaille, circa 1950 (Box 5, Folder 63)
  - Bill and Doris Boynton,circa 1965-1980 (Box 5, Folder 64)
  - Ellen Bransten, circa 1957 (Box 5, Folder 65)
  - Marilee Brelage, circa 1969-1974 (Box 5, Folder 66)
  - Brooklyn Museum, 1944 (Box 5, Folder 67)
  - Philip Buckler, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 68)
  - Betty and Bob Buffum, circa 1960-1996 (Box 5, Folder 69)
  - Helen Burke, circa 1959-1966, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 70)
  - Betty Burnham, 1981-1993 (Box 5, Folder 71)
  - Alberto and Minsa Burri, 1956-1985 (Box 5, Folder 72)
  - Miscellaneous Ca-Ch, 1954-1990 (Box 5, Folder 73)
  - Miscellaneous Cl-Cu, 1954-1990 (Box 5, Folder 74)
  - California School of Fine Arts, 1951-1958 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Carl Schlosberg Fine Arts, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Jae Carmichael, circa 1972-1994, (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 3-4)
  - Dorothy Cater, circa 1958-1962 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Cemrel, Inc., 1974 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Huguette Charpentier, circa 1962-1963 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Hsiao Chin, 1957-1958 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Francois and Jean Choay, circa 1963-1992 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Cinema 16, 1949-1950 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - CINE, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Camilla Collins, circa 1958-1980, (3 folders) (Box 6, Folder 12-14)
  - Dallas Conklin, circa 1958-1980, (3 folders) (Box 6, Folder 15-17)
  - Coos Art Museum, circa 1979-1995 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Barbara Cott, circa 1970-1978 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Olive Cowell, 1956-1984, (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 20-21)
  - Pat and Dale Cox, circa 1972-1994 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Minsa Craig, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Adelyn Cross, circa 1952-1970 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Merce Cunningham, circa 1960 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Victor Cusack, 1963-1993 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Miscellaneous D, 1963-1993 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - David Anderson Gallery, 1983, 1985-1991, (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 28-29)
  - Daytona Art Institute, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Anthony Denny, circa 1957-1960 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Margaret DePatta, circa 1950 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Rose Desser, circa 1965-1984 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - V. P. Dhamija, 1971-1982 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Diane Divelbess, 1978-1992 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Philippe Dotremont, circa 1952-1965 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Dorothy Rosenthal Gallery, 1975-1984 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - John and Kit Dreyfuss, 1954, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Camille Durand, circa 1963-1983 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Zoe Dusanne, circa 1952-1967, 1977, (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 40-41)
  - Peggie Dwight, circa 1959-1991, (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 42-43)
  - Miscellaneous E, 1949-1993 (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Garrett and Arline Eckbo, 1958-1987 (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Eckbo, Royston and Williams, circa 1947-1989, (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 46-47)
  - Jo Eckstein, circa 1958-1961 (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Ed Kearney Casting and Manufacturing, 1972-1974 (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - Larry and Yoko Elsner, circa 1972-1989 (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - Susie and Roy Eldredge, circa 1950-1989 (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - Madeleine Everaert, circa 1958-1979 (Box 6, Folder 52)
  - Experimental Printmaking, circa 1974-1981, (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 53-54)
  - Miscellaneous Fa-Fi, 1948-1994 (Box 6, Folder 55)
  - Miscellaneous Fl-Fu, 1948-1994 (Box 6, Folder 56)
  - Shirley and Isadore Familian, circa 1984-1993 (Box 6, Folder 57)
  - Perl Fine, 1947 (Box 6, Folder 58)
  - Hanna and Ted Finklestein, 1983-1986 (Box 6, Folder 59)
  - Alfonso de Fortuna, 1974-1975 (Box 6, Folder 60)
  - Fredericke Fourcaud, circa 1958-1989 (Box 6, Folder 61)
  - Francine Seders Gallery, 1972-1973 (Box 6, Folder 62)
  - Sam and Muriel Francis, circa 1950-1966 (Box 6, Folder 63)
  - Betty Freeman, circa 1963-1974 (Box 6, Folder 64)
  - Raymonde Frin, circa 1952-1986 (Box 6, Folder 65)
  - Carlo Frua, circa 1955-1970 (Box 6, Folder 66)
  - Fullerton Bicentennial Committee, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 67)
  - Miscellaneous G, 1959-1992 (Box 6, Folder 68)
  - Galerie Anderson-Mayer, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 69)
  - Galerie Rive Droite, circa 1956 (Box 6, Folder 70)
  - Galerie Stadler, circa 1957-1993, (4 folders) (Box 7, Folder 1-4)
  - Galleria Di Spazio, circa 1956 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Gallery Mayer, 1959-1962 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Gallery of Modern Art, Scottsdale, circa 1966-1968 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Gene Autry Western Heritage Museum, 1994-1995 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Nancy Genn, circa 1959-1984 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Harriet Germain, 1961, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Andre Gibert, circa 1951-1952 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Peter Gimpel, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Mark and Erno Goldfinger, circa 1968-1979 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Gordon Woodside Galleries, 1968-1969 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Grafico Uno, 1952-1990, (3 folders) (Box 7, Folder 15-17)
  - Ollie Kate and Paul Green, 1944-1980 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Ray Green, circa 1952-1992 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Anne Gregory, circa 1987-1994 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Anna Gruen, 1931-1932 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Trude Guetzmonprez, circa 1950-1970 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Peggy Guggenheim, circa 1961-1979 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Uuie Guiette, 1957-1961 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Margo Gwinn, 1950-1963 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Miscellaneous Ha, circa 1947-1987 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Miscellaneous He-Hy, circa 1958-1993 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Yvonne Hagen, circa 1955-1992, (2 folders) (Box 7, Folder 28-29)
  - Don Ham, circa 1976-1991 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Lois Handler, 1990-1994 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Walter Hanlon, 1953-1954 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Jo Hanson, circa 1984-1990 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Lena Hansen, 1984-1996, (2 folders) (Box 7, Folder 34-35)
  - Sylvia Hartman, 1974-1992 (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Paul and Virginia Hassel, circa 1950-1960 (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Anne Hauberg, circa 1971-1990, (3 folders) (Box 7, Folder 38-40)
  - Ashley Haviden, circa 1950-1953 (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - Bill and Desiree Hayter, circa 1979 (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - Marin Henderson, circa 1981-1993 (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - Louis Heyn, circa 1968-1981 (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - Ron Hickman, circa 1983 (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - Lynn Hickey, circa 1981-1987 (Box 7, Folder 46)
  - F. M. Hinkhouse, circa 1968-1986 (Box 7, Folder 47)
  - Eden Hodara, circa 1953-1970 (Box 7, Folder 48)
  - House Beautiful, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 49)
  - Hollis Galleries, 1966-1970 (Box 7, Folder 50)
  - Bruce and Betye Howell, circa 1964-1997 (Box 7, Folder 51)
  - Mildred Hudson, 1977-1978 (Box 7, Folder 52)
  - Frances Hussey, 1963-1974 (Box 7, Folder 53)
  - Miscellaneous I, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 54)
  - Institute of Contemporary Arts, 1953-1968 (Box 7, Folder 55)
  - il segno, 1957-1958 (Box 7, Folder 56)
  - Miscellaneous Ja-Ju, circa 1951-1986 (Box 7, Folder 57)
  - Jack Rutberg Fine Arts, 1985-1993 (Box 7, Folder 58)
  - Edward Jacobson, 1976-1984 (Box 7, Folder 59)
  - Sam and Bettye Jaffe, 1980-1985 (Box 7, Folder 60)
  - Paul Jenkins, circa 1954-1968 (Box 7, Folder 61)
  - Gertrude Flint Jones, 1947-1969 (Box 7, Folder 62)
  - Judy Miller Publications, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 63)
  - Miscellaneous K, circa 1958-1993 (Box 7, Folder 64)
  - Maggie (Ann) Karl, 1958, 1987-1993 (Box 7, Folder 65)
  - Bruce Kasmer, 1991-1993 (Box 7, Folder 66)
  - Karl and Georgette Kasten, circa 1961-1991, (2 folders) (Box 7, Folder 67-68)
  - Lila Katzen, 1960-1969 (Box 7, Folder 69)
  - KCET, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 70)
  - Jim and Jane Kresl, circa 1969-1981 (Box 7, Folder 71)
  - Katherine Kuh, circa 1956-1992 (Box 7, Folder 72)
  - Walter Kuhlman, circa 1953-1963 (Box 7, Folder 73)
  - Miscellaneous La, 1945-1996 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous Le-Lu, 1945-1996 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Laguna Art Museum, 1993-1995 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Nancy Lang, 1944-1990 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Estelle and Erwine Laverne, circa 1965 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Ora Lerman, 1980-1993 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Judy and Murry Lerner, circa 1961-1962 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Edith and Arthur Levin, 1979-1986 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Orme and Barbara Lewis, 1968-1981 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Charles and Miriam Lindstrom, circa 1951-1992 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Frank Lobdell, circa 1950-1974 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Pat Logan, circa 1971-1993 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Emmanuel Looten, circa 1956-1959 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - City of Los Angeles, 1968-1974 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Sam and Shirley Lichtman, 1968-1982 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Linda Farris Galleries, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Los Angeles County Museum of Art, 1967-1991 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - George Lusk, circa 1947-1950 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Herbert Lust, circa 1961-1962 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Miscellaneous Ma-Mc, 1947-1993 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Miscellaneous Me-Mu, 1947-1993 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Francis McCann, circa 1950-1974 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Richard McCarthy, 1944-1997, (8 folders) (Box 8, Folder 23-30)
  - Lucille McEnery, 1975-1976 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Carl W. McIntosh, 1965-1973 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Eline McKnight, circa 1951-1964 (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Charlotte Mack, 1959-1965 (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - MAI Gallery, 1957-1959 (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Malvina Miller Gallery, circa 1971-1974 (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - Manina, circa 1962 (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Phyllis Manley, 1961, 1971-1980 (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - Marilyn Pearl Gallery, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - Paolo Marinotti, 1959-1973 (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - Marva Marrow, circa 1987 (Box 8, Folder 41)
  - M'Arte, 1970-1971 (Box 8, Folder 42)
  - Martha Jackson Gallery, 1955-1981, (4 folders) (Box 8, Folder 43-46)
  - Paolo and Florence Marzotto, 1963-1988 (Box 8, Folder 47)
  - Media Gallery, 1972, 1976, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 48)
  - June Meehan, 1953-1961 (Box 8, Folder 49)
  - Lani Miller, circa 1970-1993 (Box 8, Folder 50)
  - Mills College, 1947-1955, 1977, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 51)
  - Florence Minard, circa 1938-1980 (Box 8, Folder 52)
  - Nick Minginourch, 1969-1970,1983, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 53)
  - Peter Mitten, 1984-1991 (Box 8, Folder 54)
  - Sybil Moholy-Nagy, circa 1950 (Box 8, Folder 55)
  - Daniel Mondschein, 1990-1991 (Box 8, Folder 56)
  - Luigi Moretti, circa 1955-1973, (2 folders) (Box 8, Folder 57-58)
  - Grace Morley, 1955, 1981-1985 (Box 8, Folder 59)
  - Berto Morucchio, circa 1954-1984, (4 folders) (Box 8, Folder 60-63)
  - Bob Mosher, circa 1960 (Box 8, Folder 64)
  - Leota Moulton, circa 1960-1976 (Box 8, Folder 65)
  - Jean and Agnes de Moustier, circa 1956-1962 (Box 8, Folder 66)
  - Tuni Murtinho, 1953-1955 (Box 8, Folder 67)
  - Museum of Modern Art, 1947-1977 (Box 8, Folder 68)
  - Miscellaneous N, 1950-1993 (Box 8, Folder 69)
  - Bernie and Ruth Nath, circa 1957-1988 (Box 8, Folder 70)
  - National Collection of Fine Arts, Smithsonian, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 71)
  - National Museum of American Art, 1982, 1990-1997 (Box 8, Folder 72)
  - Neill Gallery, circa 1976-1983, (2 folders) (Box 8, Folder 73-74)
  - David Nellis, circa 1970-1973 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Fred and Eva Neumayer, circa 1950-1951, 1955 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Norton Simon Museum, circa 1987 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous O, circa 1961-1984 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Oakland Museum of Art, 1959-1982, 1994-1995 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Oakland Public Schools, 1947 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Wally and Dotty Obers, circa 1963-1972 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Francine O'Donnell, 1982, 1984, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - May O'Donnell, 1948-1994, (2 folders) (Box 9, Folder 9-10)
  - Ella Odorfer, 1965-1975 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Nanon Ohman, circa 1975-1986 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Flora and John Olsen, 1960-1980 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Don and Helen Olsen, circa 1953-1980 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Orr's Gallery, 1975-1976 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Alfonzo Ossorio, 1960-1990 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Otto Seligman Gallery, 1954-1963 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Judy Owyang, 1970-1972 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous Pa-Pe, circa 1949-1994 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Miscellaneous Ph-Py, circa 1949-1994 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Eduardo Paolozzi, circa 1952 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - David Parry, circa 1966-1993, (2 folders) (Box 9, Folder 22-23)
  - Stella Patri, circa 1958-1992 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Giacomo Patri, 1951, 1969-1978 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Celia Payton, 1954-1967 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Ellie Persons, 1968-1969, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Amy Phelps, 1950-1951 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Joann and Gifford Phillips, circa 1973-1988 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Phoenix Art Museum, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Jean Piaubert, 1966, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Polly Friedlander Gallery, 1973-1978, (3 folders) (Box 9, Folder 32-34)
  - Miscellaneous Q, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Miscellaneous Ra-Ri, 1949-1996 (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Miscellaneous Ro-Ry, 1949-1996 (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - Robert Ramsey, 1966-1986 (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - Herbert Read, 1950-1967 (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - Ted and Hanna Renneker, 1969, 1980-1996 (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - Jeanne Reynal, circa 1957-1966 (Box 9, Folder 41)
  - Riggs Galleries, circa 1989-1991 (Box 9, Folder 42)
  - Terry Riley, 1968-1985 (Box 9, Folder 43)
  - Esther and Bob Robles, circa 1960-1983, (2 folders) (Box 9, Folder 44-45)
  - Mildred Rosenthal, circa 1951-1969 (Box 9, Folder 46)
  - Alix de Rothschild, circa 1963-1976 (Box 9, Folder 47)
  - Pierre and Jacqueline Roumeguere, 1958-1974 (Box 9, Folder 48)
  - Evelyn Royston, 1966-1967 (Box 9, Folder 49)
  - Evelyn and Bob Royston, circa 1953-1985 (Box 9, Folder 50)
  - Sam and Gladys Rubenstein, circa 1971-1995, (2 folders) (Box 9, Folder 51-52)
  - David Rubin, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 53)
  - Virginia Russ, circa 1944-1954 (Box 9, Folder 54)
  - Miscellaneous Sa-Se, circa 1948-1996 (Box 9, Folder 55)
  - Miscellaneous Sh-Sm, circa 1948-1996 (Box 9, Folder 56)
  - Miscellaneous Sn-Sw, circa 1948-1996 (Box 9, Folder 57)
  - Sacramento Metropolitan Arts Commission, 1982-1985 (Box 9, Folder 58)
  - SalviatiEc., circa 1968-1973, (2 folders) (Box 9, Folder 59-60)
  - San Diego Fine Arts Gallery, 1973-1976 (Box 9, Folder 61)
  - San Francisco Chronicle, 1951-1956 (Box 9, Folder 62)
  - San Francisco Museum of Modern Art, circa 1948-1991, (2 folders) (Box 10, Folder 1-2)
  - Kenneth Sawyer, circa 1948-1963, (2 folders) (Box 10, Folder 3-4)
  - Morton and Kay Schamberg, circa 1964-1977 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Bonnie Schwartz, circa 1979-1980 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Mel and Gerrie Scott, 1948-1949, 1968-1977 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Seattle Art Museum, 1974-1975, 1996 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Seligman Gallery, 1967-1968 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Henry Seldis, 1974-1978 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Senior Group, 1969-1985, (2 folders) (Box 10, Folder 11-12)
  - I. Serpan, 1954 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Elaine Sewell, 1975, 1982-1993 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Gertrude Shurr, 1944-1993 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Amy Silen, 1977-1991 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Nell Sinton, 1960-1977 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Wendy Slatkin, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Smith Andersen Gallery, circa 1975-1985, (2 folders) (Box 10, Folder 19-20)
  - Hans Snock and Erik De Vries, circa 1952-1957, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Flora Soldan, circa 1962-1972 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Solomon R. Guggenheim Museum, 1945-1980 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Selden Spaulding, circa 1962-1969 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Darthea Speyer, 1952-1992 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Katie Stedman, circa 1947-1979 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Leonard and Marie Stein, circa 1969-1986 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Joe and Margaret Stein, circa 1952-1993 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Vivienne Stein, circa 1985-1993 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Stephen Wirtz Gallery, 1984-1985 (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - Clyfford and Pat Still, 1955-1985, (2 folders) (Box 10, Folder 31-32)
  - Angie Strickland, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - Louise Svendsen, 1973-1976 (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - Jayne Sword, 1952-1958 (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - Miscellaneous T, 1959-1993 (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - Jean-Marc Tapie, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - Michel Tapie, 1953-1981, (2 folders) (Box 10, Folder 38-39)
  - Antonio Tapies, 1956-1957 (Box 10, Folder 40)
  - Tate Gallery, 1970-1979 (Box 10, Folder 41)
  - Ron Tatro, 1978-1983 (Box 10, Folder 42)
  - Alan Temko, circa 1951-1996, (2 folders) (Box 10, Folder 43-44)
  - Susannah Temko, 1964-1985, (4 folders) (Box 10, Folder 45-48)
  - Thank You Notes, circa 1958-1990 (Box 10, Folder 49)
  - Thank You Notes from Students, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 50)
  - Yvonne Thibaut-Pomerantz, 1965-1982 (Box 10, Folder 51)
  - John Thomas, circa 1981-1985 (Box 10, Folder 52)
  - Ruth Thompson, 1949-1989 (Box 10, Folder 53)
  - Elizabeth Tiso, 1982-1988 (Box 10, Folder 54)
  - Tobey Moss Gallery, 1980-1993 (Box 10, Folder 55)
  - Mark Tobey, 1954-1979, (4 folders) (Box 10, Folder 56-59)
  - Torque Gallery, 1982, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 60)
  - Miscellaneous U, 1949, 1972, 1977-1994 (Box 10, Folder 61)
  - University of Oregon, Museum of Art, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 62)
  - Miscellaneous V, 1960-1994 (Box 10, Folder 63)
  - Dorothy and George Vaughan, circa 1974-1993 (Box 10, Folder 64)
  - Jean Villeri, circa 1950-1952 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Vogue, 1958 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous W, 1950-1995 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Esther Waite, circa 1960-1984 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Grace Marie Waldrup, circa 1972-1994 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Gordon and Ruth Washburn, circa 1959-1976 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - June Wayne, circa 1953-1984 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Wes Wehr, 1956-1979 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Marcia Weisman, circa 1966-1986 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Woty Werner, 1951-1957 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Wilhelm Wessel, 1957-1962 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Glenn Wessels, circa 1950 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Katherine White, circa 1970-1980 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Frans Wildenhain, circa 1949-1960, (2 folders) (Box 11, Folder 14-15)
  - Charlotte Willard, circa 1960-1976 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - George Wittenborn, 1955-1960 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Laura Jane and Hamilton Wolf, circa 1936-1965, (2 folders) (Box 11, Folder 18-19)
  - Myrtle and Frank Wolf, circa 1950-1997, (5 folders) (Box 11, Folder 20-24)
  - Woman's Building, 1985-1987 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Women's Caucus of Art, 1979-1983 (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Jason Wong, circa 1968-1993, (2 folders) (Box 11, Folder 27-28)
  - O. J. Woodward, circa 1969-1976 (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - Worcester Art Museum, 1993-1994 (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - Miscellaneous Y, 1960-1984 (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - Miscellaneous Z, 1984, 1990 (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - First Names Only, undated (Box 11, Folder 33)
  - First Names Only, circa 1945-1969 (Box 11, Folder 34)
  - First Names Only, circa 1970-1988 (Box 11, Folder 35)
  - First Names Only, circa 1991-1996 (Box 11, Folder 36)
  - Postcards, circa 1940-1997 (Box 11)
  - Christmas Cards, circa 1940-1960 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Christmas Cards, circa 1961-1996 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Christmas Cards, 1959 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Christmas Cards, 1964-1973, (21 folders) (Box 12, Folder 4-24)
  - Christmas Cards, 1973-1997, (29 folders) (Box 13, Folder 1-29)
  - Christmas Cards from Claire Falkenstein, circa 1963-1995 (Box 13, Folder 30)
- Personal and Business Records, 1936-1997, Series 3:; (Box 14-17, 41, 46-49; 4.2 linear feet)
  Personal and business records contain a wide variety of material documenting Falkenstein's business, financial, legal, professional, and personal transactions. Files are found for sales and prices of artwork, artwork inventories, smaller jewelry commissions, speaking engagements, her extensive work as a juror, her business with galleries, legal affairs and contracts, expenses, records of arts organizations to which she belonged, conferences, grants and fellowships, studio and house renovations, her Paris studio and Paris expenses, travel, donations, loans and consignments, conservation, art shipping, insurance, and taxes. The records provide detailed information on her business relationships with several galleries. The renovation files document Falkenstein's conversion of her house into a living space with working studio. Oversized visitor's logs contain comments from visitors to Falkenstein's studio in Venice, California.
  The files are arranged alphabetically by subject and folder contents are arranged chronologically.
  - Accounts, 1969-1997 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Air France, 1952-1953 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - American Abstract Artists, 1950 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - American Reference Publishing Corporation, 1988-1989 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - American Studio Jewelry Since 1940, 1988-1989 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Annual Conference of the Alliance of California Arts Councils, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Architects, 1988-1989 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Art Books Sold, 1995 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Art Jewelry Limited, 1986 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Artpark Programs, 1976-1978 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Art Storage and Transport - Invoices, 1950-1955 (Box 14, Folder 11)